How scary.
真是可怕
This is most likely a spell that slices through objects.
这八成是能够把物体切开的魔法
The spell itself is a simple one,
魔法本身很简单
but I can't see its trajectory.
但我看不出其中轨迹
It's impossible to dodge all of them. However…
要全部躲过是不可能的 不过…
What's wrong? You're not going to come after me?
怎么了？不继续跟过来了？
I may have lost control of myself a bit.
我稍微有点失控了呢
Yeah…
说得是呢
The range of your magic is about five meters, isn't it?
你魔法的攻击范围 应该只有五公尺吧？
That's correct. So, what are you going to do about it?
答对了 所以你打算怎么对付？
Shall we go back to firing basic magic?
要再回去用基础魔法互相攻击吗？
No, there's no need for that.
不 没有那个必要
His magic has absolutely no class, is cowardly,
他的魔法毫无品行可言
and is only meant to bring him victory.
纯粹只为取胜
That girl who is fighting Wirbel
现在跟维亚贝鲁战斗的那个女孩
is probably going to get killed.
很可能会被杀掉
Well then…
那么…
A saturation attack?
饱和攻击？
How can she handle this much offensive magic at once?
她怎么能够同时发动 如此大量的攻击魔法？
What are you thinking, relying on a brute-force attack?
竟然想靠蛮力取胜？是笨蛋吗？
You have absolutely no class!
根本没有品行可言！
I can't keep up.
要防不住了
ORIGINAL STORY BY KANEHITO YAMADA / TSUKASA ABE
（原作：山田钟人 作画：阿部司）
Sorganeil.
目光束缚魔法
I can't move my body.
身体动不了了
I can't control my mana either?
也不能控制魔力吗？
A powerful restraining spell, huh?
是强力的拘束魔法啊？
If he can use something like this, why can't he catch a Stille himself?
如果能使用这种魔法 那他自己去抓陨铁鸟不就好了吗？
Well, I guess it's useless unless he can actually find a Stille.
不过找不到陨铁鸟的话 会这种魔法也是枉然
My magic can restrain whoever is within my sight.
我的魔法可以束缚住我视线中的对象
As long as I keep my eyes on you, you won't be able to move.
只要不把视线从你身上移开 你就动弹不得了
In your current state,
以你这种状态来看
I can kill you with ease.
要杀掉你简直易如反掌
And it seems he was going easy on us.
而且看来他还对我们手下留情了
If he really wanted to kill us,
如果他真的想杀我们的话
he would have restrained us during that surprise attack.
刚才的突袭就可以封住我们的行动
This is your last chance.
这是你最后一次机会
Leave the Stille behind and go.
留下陨铁鸟 然后滚蛋
Oh, how boring.
什么嘛 真是无聊
I was looking forward to fighting him to the death.
本来还很期待跟他来场殊死战
In the end, all he wanted to do was extort the Stille.
结果他就只想威胁我们交出陨铁鸟啊
Wait a second.
等一下
Why do you have to make that order?
你干嘛还要下这种命令？
You can just take the Stille away from me while I can't move.
你大可在我无法动弹的时候 拿走陨铁鸟就好了
So it doesn't work unless my entire body is within view, huh?
看来这个魔法 只有在看到我全身时才能发挥作用？
No wonder you don't use it against multiple people.
难怪人多的时候无法使用
-You aimed for my eyes, didn't you? -It's logical, isn't it?
-瞄准我的眼睛 是吧？ -这是合理的判断吧？
No,
不
if I were you, I would've aimed for the neck to kill my target.
换作是我就会砍掉对方的头
Then the battle would be over.
这样一来就结束战斗了
You could have done that too.
你应该也能够办到才对
There were people who acted like you on the battlefield too.
战场上也有跟你做出同样行动的人
They were all perverts who enjoyed killing.
那些人全都是以杀人作乐的变态
I'd better kill you here.
看来我最好在这里把你杀掉
Have you ever killed women and children?
你有杀过女人跟小孩吗？
You think I haven't?
你以为我没有吗？
What kind of horror did you experience?
你究竟见过了什么样的地狱啊？
Are you trying to buy time?
这是在争取时间吗？
Fine, I'll play along.
好吧 我就告诉你吧
The Northern Magic Corps is
我所属的北部魔法队
a group of mercenaries specializing in fighting demons.
是专门跟魔族战斗的佣兵部队
But in an emergency, we also fight international warfare.
但遇上紧急情况时 我们也会参与国与国之间的战争
People are well aware of their own weaknesses.
人都很清楚自身的弱点
Forcing women and children onto the battlefield is diabolical
逼女人跟小孩上战场虽然泯灭人性
but also a very common act.
却是相当常见的作法
It's not "horror."
那可不是什么地狱
That's everyday life in the north.
那是北方生活的日常
Is that so?
是这样吗？
That's enough.
已经够了
You're not going to kill me?
你不杀我吗？
In my opinion, the type of magic one specializes in
我认为 一个人专精的魔法种类
greatly reflects their life and character.
相当能够反映出 那个人经历的人生与性格
This magic, which restrains the target's movements,
这种封住对方行动的魔法
makes it seem like you want to delay their death.
感觉就好像 让你在下手之前能有点犹豫的时间
I see…
原来如此
So that's why you played along with my tactic to buy time?
也是因为这样 你才任由我拖延时间啊？
How surprising.
真是令人意外
Your hands are stained with blood already,
明明双手早就沾满血迹了
but you still wish to be human, huh?
但却还想好好当个人吗？
That's right.
没错
This is the time I need to find my resolve to kill.
这是让我做好杀人觉悟的时间
But you know, little girl,
不过呢 小姐
I may hesitate and waver,
我也许会犹豫、会动摇
but I've never failed a necessary killing.
但该动手的时候可不会失手
Goodbye, little girl.
永别了 小姐
Don't move, please.
请你不要动
Are you serious? You took down Ehre?
不是吧？艾露被你干掉了？
I didn't sense her presence at all.
我竟然完全察觉不到她的气息
I'm surprised. You're able to make your mana disappear completely?
真是令人惊讶 你竟然能让自己的魔力完全消失？
You must be the one who caught the Stille.
抓住陨铁鸟的人一定就是你吧
We were just lucky.
只不过是运气好罢了
We happened to find the Stille's nest,
我们偶然发现了陨铁鸟的鸟窝
and she had learned the spell that captures a bird from her master.
而她在她师父那里学过抓鸟的魔法
You can capture anything,
明明你什么都能抓住
but it seems you are really unlucky.
看来你实在运气不好呢
Seriously. I'm out of luck.
真的呢 我运气真是烂透了
You were fighting Ehre, weren't you? What did you do with her?
你刚刚不是在跟艾露战斗吗？ 你把她怎么了？
I killed her.
杀掉了
The conditions to pass the first stage of the exam were
通过第一阶段考试的条件
to have a caged Stille in your possession by sundown today
就是在今天日落前 得到关有陨铁鸟的笼子
and to have all party members present.
以及小队成员全员到场
We've lost.
我们已经输了
I'll be leaving.
我要走了
Weren't you going to kill me?
刚刚你不是要杀我吗？
We are officially disqualified.
我们已经不合格了
Killing you is unnecessary now.
现在没必要杀你了
Bye.
再见了
Feel free to aim for my back.
想从背后偷袭我也没关系喔
It will only turn an unnecessary killing back into a necessary one.
只不过原本没必要杀你 现在就变成有必要了
-Mistress Übel. -I know.
-尤贝尔大人 -知道了啦
You're a good liar.
你还真是会说谎
Let's go assist Master Land while we can.
趁现在赶紧去帮兰托大人吧
I'm sure he's fine.
他没问题的
Four-eyes seems to be quite the trickster.
那个眼镜男似乎也很擅长骗人
The game's over.
胜负揭晓了
That's amazing.
还真是厉害
You controlled countless steel flower petals with precision
竟然能精准操控无数的钢铁花瓣
and slipped through my defense.
避开我的防御
But I bet it's self-taught.
不过这是自创的招数吧
Self-taught people tend to neglect the basics.
无师自通的人 总是会忽略最基本的东西
Before I fight against someone I don't know,
和不熟悉的对手交战前
I always remember to observe first.
我都会记得要先观察对方
I know your weakness very well.
你的弱点我非常清楚
I'm pretty sure I'll win.
我十有八九是赢定了
You're quite the chatterbox.
废话还真多呢
How do you plan to win without using your dominant arm?
你不用惯用手 打算怎么赢我？
If you won't surrender, I will cut your head off next.
你不投降的话 下次我就会砍掉你的头
Like I said, I'm just observing before I fight.
正如我所说的 战斗之前我只会先观察
I bet you're not good at mana detection.
你应该很不擅长魔力感知吧
Phantom magic?
幻影魔法？
I actually exist, so it's more like my clone.
我可是真实存在的 这更应该说是我的分身
Since when--
什么时候…
From the beginning.
打从最初的时候
From the moment the first stage began.
从第一阶段考试开始的时候
I don't trust others.
毕竟我不信任他人
"Killed her" my ass.
说什么“杀掉了”
That bitch lied to me like it was nothing.
那个臭女人在我眼前撒谎跟喝水一样
Hey, wake up, Ehre.
喂 醒醒 艾露
You ran out of mana? How lame.
魔力用完了？逊毙了
Weren't you top of your class?
你不是魔法学校班上的第一名吗？
I was beaten by her sheer amount of ordinary offensive magic.
她光靠大量的 一般攻击魔法就打倒我了
I couldn't keep up with it all.
我完全无法抵挡
You don't believe me, do you?
你不相信我吧？
No, I do.
我信你
You're an idiot for fighting her head-on.
正面迎战她的你才是个笨蛋
You should have been able to win.
你本来有机会可以赢的
But if she can do this much with just ordinary offensive magic,
但如果单靠一般攻击魔法 她就能做到这种程度
that woman must be quite the monster.
那个女人肯定跟怪物没两样
Let's go. We'll meet up with Scharf.
走吧 去跟夏鲁夫会合
Wait, I can't walk.
等一下 我走不了路了
Jeez…
真是拿你没办法
Hey!
喂！
Don't transport me like I'm cargo. Give me a piggyback ride!
不要把我当作货物来搬啊 好好把我背在背上！
Why do I have to do this?
我干嘛要做这种事啊？
Do you sense Scharf nearby?
有感知到夏鲁夫在附近了吗？
He's on the other side of that thicket.
他在灌木丛的另一边
Hey, Scharf! Help me carry Ehre…
喂 夏鲁夫！帮我背艾露…
Wirbel, please give me a piggyback ride.
维亚贝鲁 麻烦你背我一程
I'm all numb and can't move.
我身体麻掉了 动弹不得
Damn it! Why is this happening?
可恶 到底为什么会这样啊？
What is this sound?
这是什么声音？
It must be the sound of rain.
想也知道是雨声
It started raining outside of the barrier.
结界外开始在下雨了
It's like a representation of my mental state.
简直跟我的精神状态一样
In two to three hours it'll be sundown
再过两、三个小时就日落了
and the first stage will end.
第一阶段考试也就结束了
We have two members out of commission.
两名成员无法战斗
We can't steal a Stille in this state anymore.
这样也无法再盗走陨铁鸟了
We've failed this exam for sure.
这次考试肯定不会通过了
But you're still going to help us? You must be very kind.
尽管如此 你还是来救我们了 还真是温柔呢
I wouldn't mind abandoning you two right here.
马上丢下你们我也无所谓喔
-Don't leave us. -Stop crying. Act like a man!
-请不要丢下我们 -别哭了 像个男人好吗！
Is that kindness also the reason why you fight demons?
这种温柔也是 你与魔族战斗的理由吗？
You saved my village too.
你也拯救了我的村子
Don't be stupid.
别傻了
Why would I risk my life out of kindness?
我哪可能出于温柔而拿性命去冒险？
Humans fight for their own desires.
人都是为了自己的欲望而战
I had an ulterior motive.
我本来是另有所图
In my hometown, I had a crush.
我在家乡有过喜欢的人
It was exactly 29 years ago.
那正是距今29年前的事
Demons were becoming more active in the northern lands,
魔族在北方诸国愈来愈活跃
so she and her whole family ran away to the central lands.
所以她跟她家人就逃到中央诸国去了
I was a dumb little kid, so I tried to act cool.
我当时是个蠢小子 就只想耍帅
I'll kill every one of those darn demons.
我要杀光那些该死的魔族
So come back to this village when I do.
到时候你一定要回来村里
I was about four or five years old.
我那时候才四、五岁大吧
I don't even remember her face or name.
连她的名字或是脸蛋都记不起来了
-What a fool. -I know, I'm a fool.
-真是个笨蛋呢 -是啊 我是个笨蛋
I have to go back by sea again.
必须再走海路回去了
I get really seasick, you know.
我很会晕船耶
Want me to refer you to my grandfather?
要我介绍我老爷子给你吗？
He's a first-class mage, so you can go by land…
他是一级魔法使 那你就能走陆路了…
Hey, Wirbel.
喂 维亚贝鲁
-What's wrong? -Look.
-怎么了？ -你看那个
You've got to be kidding. What was all that work for?
这是在开玩笑吧 那我们刚刚何苦大费周章？
It took way too long for my luck to turn around.
这么久才轮到我走运一回
Frieren, that girl hasn't made any move.
芙莉莲 那个女孩 从刚刚开始就一动也不动
An elf, huh?
精灵吗？
She must be a capable mage.
肯定是很杰出的魔法使
I'm sure Laufen's magic
拉奥芬的魔法只要
won't work on her again, if she sees it even once.
被她看到一次 就对她不起作用了
But once is more than enough.
但一次也绰绰有余了
This isn't a fight to the death.
毕竟没有要置对方于死地
-She disappeared! -Frieren, the Stille!
-消失了！ -芙莉莲 陨铁鸟！
It was taken, huh?
被抢走了啊？
What interesting magic.
真是有趣的魔法
It's pleasant inside the barrier even when it's raining.
下雨时待在结界里还真是惬意
You were the proctor for the second stage, weren't you,
话说 你是第二阶段考试的考官吧？
Sense?
赞泽
It appears you've let many promising examinees die yet again, Genau.
盖纳乌 看来你这次 又让几个明日之星丧命了
Don't make me laugh.
别说笑了
If they were promising, they wouldn't have died this easily.
真正的明日之星 哪会这么容易丧命？
Plus, the value of first-class mages makes it worth it.
而且一级魔法使的价值也仅此而已
You should know that.
这点你应该也很清楚
Still, it's mean-spirited of you
就算是这样 你也很坏心眼啊
to choose a prey that can't be detected by mana in an exam for mages.
在魔法使的考试里 选了无法用魔力感知到的猎物
Whether you capture it or not depends on luck.
抓不抓的到 全凭个人运气
Fighting over the bird is just a pretense for a battle royale.
不过就是伪装成夺鸟战的大逃杀而已
Luck is part of one's ability.
运气也是实力的一部份
Plus, some of them seem to have captured a Stille without using luck.
而且好像也有人 不是凭运气抓到陨铁鸟的呢
Sundown is in three hours.
再三个小时就日落了
The battle will get intense from here.
接下来的战斗会更激烈
Who do you think will make it?
你认为哪些人会胜出呢？
I'm sure a third of them will pass.
有三分之一的人会通过吧
Denken will definitely be one of them.
邓肯肯定会是其中之一
His abilities are on a par with that of a first-class mage.
他的实力已经可以媲美一级魔法使了
Why would an old man only interested in wealth and power
只对财富跟权力感兴趣的老人
take this exam now?
事到如今干嘛要应考呢？
Is he after the privilege?
难道是为了特权？
Who knows?
天知道
He is up in years already.
那个老爷子也上了年纪了
He must have his own reasons.
一定是有自己的理由吧
Hey, the magic that she just used right now
我说啊 她刚刚使用的魔法
was Jilwer, right?
是高速移动魔法吧？
It's folk magic from a mountain tribe in the southern lands.
是属于南方诸国山中部族的民间魔法
Yes, that's right.
没错
-Jilwer? -Magic that lets you move at high speeds.
-高速移动魔法？ -能够让你快速移动的魔法
In that case, you two should have stayed hidden.
这样的话 你们两个应该要一直躲着才对
All she had to do was run away with the Stille.
她只需要带着陨铁鸟逃走就好
Laufen is still inexperienced.
拉奥芬的经验还不够
She left too many traces of her mana.
留下太多魔力的痕迹了
You would be able to track her down easily, Frieren.
你的话一定能轻松追踪到她 芙莉莲
In fact, you must be rather annoyed that we're holding you.
其实你现在觉得我们很碍事吧
Yeah.
也是啦
You know about me?
你认识我吗？
There isn't a single mage in my generation who doesn't know your name.
我这个世代的人 没有哪个魔法使不知道你的名号
It's my first time seeing you in person, though.
尽管这是我第一次亲眼见到你本人
But I knew the moment I saw you,
但我一看到你就认出来了
that you were the mage of the party of heroes, Frieren.
你是勇者一行当中的魔法使 芙莉莲
-She's famous? -She's a legendary mage.
-她很有名吗？ -那是传说中的魔法使
I had an inkling that it was her.
我前面就隐约猜到是她了
Elves really don't age, do they?
精灵果然不会老 是吧？
So, in the end, you're going to challenge us head-on?
结果你打算要与我们正面对抗？
You were spying on us the whole time, weren't you?
你们一直都在 暗中窥伺我们的动向吧？
I expected you to use more dirty tricks.
我本以为你们会使出更肮脏的手段
Well, this is dirty enough.
这样也已经够肮脏的了
While Denken stalls you,
在邓肯拖住你的时候
I will kill either one of those brats.
我就会杀掉其中一个小鬼
I see.
原来如此
If we lose a party member and fail to meet the requirements,
小队中失去任何成员 都会无法符合合格条件
we will have no choice but to give up.
那我们就不得不放弃了
Interesting. Why don't you try?
有意思 放马过来啊
-Lawine, he's strong. -I know.
-拉比涅 这家伙很强 -我知道
Stop it, Richter.
住手 利希塔
As long as we can stall them, that's enough.
只要能拖住她们就够了
We can win this.
这样我们就赢定了
Denken, I thought you would be a more ruthless and cold person.
邓肯 我还以为 你是个更加冷酷无情的人呢
Aren't you an Imperial Mage?
你不是宫廷魔法使吗？
I'm sure you've eliminated more than enough political enemies.
至今应该也消灭过不少政敌吧
I just don't think that becoming
我只是觉得不值得
a first-class mage is worth killing someone over.
为了当上一级魔法使而杀人
I can agree with you on that, at least.
至少这一点我赞成你的看法
A first-class mage is nothing more than a title.
一级魔法使不过是个称号罢了
It's not worth it in my opinion.
就我看来没有任何价值
Unbelievable.
真是难以置信
Don't tell me you don't know about the privilege?
难道你连特权都不知道就来应考了？
Privilege?
特权？
Half a century ago, the founder of the Continental Magic Association
半个世纪以前 大陆魔法协会的创办人
who reigns over all of mankind's mages,
也是所有人类魔法使的统治者
suddenly came into the limelight.
突然出现在人们面前
That is the Great Mage Serie.
大魔法使赛丽艾
She is still pursuing mages like those who were refined during the long war
她仍然在追求与魔王军长年对战
against the Demon King's army.
那些千锤百炼的魔法使
That is why she has
正因如此
promised a privilege to those who rise to the rank of first-class mage.
她才承诺要给 晋升为一级魔法使的人一项特权
She will bestow upon them one spell of their choice.
她会教他们一个他们所渴望的魔法
Serie is a living grimoire who knows almost every spell that has existed
赛丽艾可说是活着的魔导书 人类史上存在的所有魔法
in the history of mankind.
她都知道
She is the closest existence to the Almighty Goddess.
是这片大地上 最接近全知全能女神的存在
You can attain an enormous fortune, heal a serious illness,
你可以获得 巨大的财富、治愈重大疾病
or even gain tremendous power.
或得到至高无上的权力
Being bestowed with whatever spell you desire
能够学到自己最渴望的魔法
is any mage's dream come true.
对魔法使而言 无异于实现梦想
People are very simple.
人啊 都是很单纯的
Because of that, first-class mages are now
拜此所赐 至今为止 成为一级魔法使的人
a group of monsters who make you doubt if they're human.
都是会让你不禁怀疑 他们是不是人类的怪物
That is how valuable it is.
这个称号就是有那种程度的价值
I see.
这样啊
That's ridiculous.
真是愚不可及
Denken, people like you, who don't care about the privilege, are the minority.
邓肯 像你这样 不在乎特权的人是少数
Let's begin.
开始吧
Denken, stall her for one minute.
邓肯 拖住她一分钟
That'll be enough time for me to kill both of them.
这点时间足够我杀掉她们两个了
Don't make me repeat myself, Richter.
别让我再重复一次 利希塔
They're just two brats.
她们不过是小鬼罢了
You only have to put them to sleep for three hours.
你只需要哄她们睡上三小时就好
-Babysitting them should be easy. -Denken…
-哄小孩很简单 你可以的吧？ -邓肯…
I will take her down.
这家伙就由老夫打倒
-That should be enough. -You old fart.
-这样就够了吧 -老糊涂
Bargland.
驭地魔法
Young ones are just too hot-blooded.
年轻人真是血气方刚
-How immature. -A spell of your choice?
-真是不成熟 -想要的魔法？
-But he has his guard down. -Come on…
-大意了 -好了…
-What a show. -I know!
-真是精采 -我知道！
-It's Frieren. -That old man.
-她叫芙莉莲 -那个老爷子
In the world of magic, heaven and earth can be turned upside down.
在魔法世界里 天地是能颠倒过来的
Subtitle translation by: Kiko Morita
字幕翻译：洪贞韵